Mekayla Trujillo

Phone: (432) 853-4199 | Email: mickeytrj@gmail.com | Odessa, TX 79763 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mekayla-truiillo-4149b4178/

GitHub: https://github.com/trujilml

Portfolio: https://trujilml.github.io/professional-coding-portfolio/

Summary

Full-stack Web Developer with a high interest in developing intuitive user experiences on mobile and web applications. Strengths in creativity, understanding new concepts, approaching and solving coding concepts and issues, offers strong collaboration and assistance when working with others.

Technical Skills and Career Qualifications

Coding Languages: Javascript, AJAX, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Responsive Web Design, Web APIs

Applications: Git, GitHub

Coding Tools: Bootstrap, jQuery

Programs: Microsoft Office 365 Programs, iOS-based iWork Productivity programs, Google Doc

Editors, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, iMovie, Procreate

Career Skills: Writing, editing, organization, interpersonal skills, clerical skills, communication, strong computing skills, and knowledge of the Windows (Microsoft) and iOS (Macintosh) operating systems

Coding Projects

Top 3 - Taco Shops

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/trujilml/top-3-taco-shops
Deployed Website: https://trujilml.github.io/top-3-taco-shops

- Summary: A taco shop website highlighting the top three taco shops in Austin, TX.
- Role: Front-End Developer, GitHub repository manager, assisted with fellow group members on design and API implementation
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Materialize, Mapbox GL JS, OpenWeather OneCall API, jQuery

Web API Coding Quiz

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/trujilml/web-api-coding-quiz Deployed Website: https://trujilml.github.io/web-api-coding-quiz/

- Summary: A timed coding guiz that allows users to understand their knowledge of JavaScript.
- Role: Sole Front-End Developer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Vacation! A Weather Dashboard

GitHub Repository: https://github.com/trujilml/vacation-weather-dashboard/
Deployed Website: https://trujilml.github.io/vacation-weather-dashboard/

- **Summary:** A weather dashboard that shows the current day forecast and five-day forecasts for your future travel destination.
- Role: Sole Front-End Developer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, ¡Query, Moment.js, OpenWeather OneCall API

Experience

Substitute Teacher Ector County Independent School District

2019 - present Odessa, TX

A substitute teacher for various schools for the Ector County Independent School District. Key Accomplishments:

- Educated students through alternative instruction provided by teachers in their absence.
- Facilitated students to additional assignments, monitored students at specific duties and provided strong classroom organization skills when required.

Permanent Substitute Teacher Murry Fly Elementary School

2020-2021

Odessa, TX

For the 2020-2021 school year, served as the day-to-day permanent substitute teacher for the Murry Fly Elementary School campus.

Key Accomplishments:

- Educated and mentored elementary students through alternative instruction.
- Provided monitor duties on the school campus and collaborated effectively with educators and staff members on campus.
- Served as a teachers' aide to select classrooms on days when no substitute teacher was required on campus.
- Performed clerical tasks and demonstrated strong organization skills as an alternative secretary or office assistant for the campus's front office.
- Assisted and resolved issues with teachers, parents, students and employees with questions or comments of school information.

Education

The University of Texas of Austin – Coding Bootcamp Accomplishing feat of Full Stack Web Development Certificate

2021 - present

Austin, TX

Currently enrolled in an online part-time Coding Bootcamp through the University of Texas at Austin to obtain a certificate in Full Stack Web Development.

- Currently practicing and acquiring web development and technical skills.
 - Demonstrates strong knowledge of web programming languages and technical skills in HTML, CSS, Responsive Design for Websites and Mobile, Javascript, AJAX, Web APIs, jQuery, Node.js, Bootstrap, and Git/GitHub deployment.

The University of Texas of the Permian Basin Bachelors of Arts in Psychology and English

2015 - 2019

Odessa, TX

Public accredited university in Odessa, Texas. Further developed career-related and personal skills from attendance and academic accomplishments.

- Authored and developed on multiple student projects such as a student-run novel.
- Senior Honors Thesis for Psychology major covered the projection of one's satisfaction with the performance of their favorite hobby.
- 4.000 GPA from enrollment, 3.420 cumulative total.
- Academic honors include the following
 - Dean's Honor Roll List Fall 2017 and Fall 2018
 - Prestigious President's List Spring 2019